Hi I'm John Graden for the Martial Arts Teacher's Association.
As a fighter and as a coach here are two offensive strategies that once you learn to understand that everything falls into place and quite simply it is a direct attack versus an indirect attack.
You want to become a master of both but the real intricacy, the real advanced student really becomes a master at the indirect attack.
What do I mean by this?
Joining me from Pro Star Mixed Martial Arts is Mr. Joe Brignoli.
A direct attack just like it implies, I am out where I set point control without a fake, without anything else, I simply step in, pow, and I directly attack him.
That is fine, however, if he is bigger, stronger, faster, more experienced than me, stepping in with a direct attack could be kind of dangerous especially if he is a really good counter fighter.
So I want to become a master of the indirect attack so possibly in this case I'm going to throw a little fake on him.
In other words I'm going to hit him with this jab but I'm going to go about it indirectly.
So I might, I've got this much distance to cover in order to get in there.
If I go direct he is going to clock me as I come in and I don't want that to happen so I go about it indirectly.
I'll throw a little fake on him, draw that punch out, and then finish the attack by stepping in the rest of the distance so it is an indirect attack.
So a direct attack, nothing proceeds it and an indirect attack is usually proceeded by a fake or some kind of draw step or something that sets the attack up.
You want to hit him with the punch or the kick but because of their counter fighting skills or speed or power you'll want to go about it indirectly.
So become a master at direct attacks and indirect attacks and when to use each.
I'm John Graden.
For more information contact me at johngraden.com.
Thank you.